# Sudhanshu

Energetic software developer with 8 years of experience developing robust code for high-volume businesses. A team player with a can-do attitude, phenomenal time management skills and a strong user focus. Has developed several mobile apps. Also understands the importance of creating highly readable and easily maintainable source code.

Gurugram +91-9958163123 anshusrivastava45@gmail.com

### **EXPERIENCE**

### **Times Internet Ltd.**, Gurugram — Sr. iOS Developer

March, 2015 - PRESENT

- Application development and R&D.
- Sprint planning and project estimation.
- Code quality and review.
- Mentoring the mobile team.

# **Techlites Solutions Pvt. Ltd.**, Delhi — *Sr. iOS Developer*

March 2014 - March 2015

- Application development, maintenance and testing.
- Sprint planning and project estimation.

# **Xicom Technologies Ltd.**, Delhi − iOS Developer

Feb 2011 - March 2014

- Application development, maintenance and testing
- Contributed in hiring mobile developers and building up team.

### **EDUCATION**

### **Kurukshetra University**, Kurukshetra — B. Tech(C.S.E.)

2005 - 2009

Percentage scored: 69.9%

# Rao Lal Singh Public School, Gurugram — Intermediate

2004 - 2005

Percentage scored: 76.7%

# Jain Public Sr. Sec. School, Dharuhera — Matriculation

2002 - 2003

Percentage scored: 81.8%

### **SKILLS**

Swift, Objective-C, Core data, SQLite, Xcode, Android Studio

#### **LANGUAGES**

Hindi, English

#### **STRENGTHS**

- Quick learner & interested to work in new challenging fields.
- Having good planning and problem solving skills.
- Motivated and dedicated to getting the job done at right time.

### **PERSONAL**

Father: Sh. Harish Chandra

Mother: Mrs. Kiran Devi

DOB: 11/11/1987 Gender: Male

Marital Status: Married

Nationality: Indian

### **PROJECTS**

**Longwalks** Times Internet Ltd.

iTunes URL:

https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/longwalks-conversation-app/id1412531085

Times Internet Ltd.

Team Size: 3-4

Longwalks app is a different type of Social Media platform which provides a guided conversation tool in a closed network. It has a fill-in-the-blanks which prompts spark personal reflection and self-expression, so user can share meaningful and create more intimate relationships.

MensXP Times Internet Ltd.

iTunes URL: <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/in/app/id1253494246?mt=8">https://itunes.apple.com/in/app/id1253494246?mt=8</a>

Team Size: 3

MensXP is India's largest lifestyle community for men. More than 15 million users in India use mensxp.com to get tips and advice on relationships, fashion, fitness, health, grooming, technology, culture, mean machines, women, sports, career, LGBT and entertainment in the context of a modern Indian man. The modern Indian man today is neither a sex-obsessed predator nor the stoic automatons our culture so often makes us out to be. We strive to be good fathers and husbands, citizens and friends, to lead by example at home and in the workplace, and to understand their role in a changing world. MensXP helps the modern Indian man discover this.

iDiva Times Internet Ltd.

iTunes URL: https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/id1359022878?ls=1&mt=8

Team Size: 2

iDiva a community for women where they can find beauty, fashion, wedding, lifestyle tips. The app also serves of original videos from iDiva actors and anchors.

**Indiatimes** Times Internet Ltd.

iTunes URL: <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/in/app/id717209912?mt=8">https://itunes.apple.com/in/app/id717209912?mt=8</a>

Team Size: 3

Indiatimes app brings you the latest news and trending stories from India and around the world. Get stories that matter to our generation. Stay up to date with all that's hot and trending with the all new Indiatimes app. We're bringing you our take on trending stories, current news and all the buzz from the world of entertainment, lifestyle, technology, sports, health and more.

Whatshot Times Internet Ltd.

iTunes URL: <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/in/app/id636515332?mt=8">https://itunes.apple.com/in/app/id636515332?mt=8</a>

Team Size: 2

What's HOT is a lifestyle product for people who loves to know new things going on in the city. It is an editorially curated discovery and exploration platform. I has *iMessages* and *Today extensions*, *Force touch shortcut* options, *Peek and pop* 

**FilmiPop** Times Internet Ltd.

iTunes URL: <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/in/app/id987892101?mt=8">https://itunes.apple.com/in/app/id987892101?mt=8</a>

Team Size: 3

Filmipop is a simple movie app that has all the latest Bollywood, Hollywood and regional Indian Movies info, trailers & reviews and local Theaters with movie showtimes. Stay up to date with all the latest happenings in Hollywood

**HeyBiz** Techlites Solutions Pvt. Ltd. iTunes URL: <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/heybiz/id945628773">https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/heybiz/id945628773</a>

Team Size: 2

HeyBiz is a messenger application that facilitates users to chat with businesses located nearby or any remote location. User can directly chat with businesses and get his/her doubts resolved without the need or visiting the store.

The above statements are true to the best of my knowledge and belief. Date: ...../......